<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Homelab Upgrade</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/homelab_upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/homelab_upgrade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a while now I have been running a Homelab (:= A server that is running at home, often with low budget hardware, hosting several applications.) using a weak Raspberry 3b, originally I was using it to better &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_0_prologue/&#34;&gt;regulate my sleep schedule&lt;/a&gt; using HomeAssistant. But over time the motivation for running my Homelab changed, I wanted to experiment more, learn about various new technologies and more philosophical I wanted to be less dependented on centralized services &amp;ndash; Like, google drive for backups, netflix for entertainment, one drive for syncing devices and many more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Basic Linux Rice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux_rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux_rice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I switched from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.debian.org/&#34;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://archlinux.org/&#34;&gt;Arch&lt;/a&gt; operating system. There were three major reasons for my switch:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Debian is often hailed as the most &lt;em&gt;stable&lt;/em&gt; operating system out there. This stability comes from the extensive testing that new software or updates undergo before being released. However, this also has a disadvantage: the software on Debian is often outdated. For example, at the time of writing this post, the latest version of Neovim available on the current Debian release (Bookworm) is &lt;code&gt;0.7.2&lt;/code&gt;, while Neovim has already released version &lt;code&gt;0.10.1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neovim Markdown Preview: Command not working</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/neovim_markdown_preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/neovim_markdown_preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;&#xA;    .info {&#xA;        background-color: #e6f7ff;  &#xA;        padding: 15px;  &#xA;        border-radius: 5px;  &#xA;        margin-bottom: 15px;  &#xA;    }&#xA;&#xA;    .info-title {&#xA;        font-size: 20px;  &#xA;        margin-bottom: 10px;  &#xA;        color: #000080;  &#xA;        font-weight: bold;  &#xA;    }&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;info&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;info-title&#34;&gt;Info&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;This post isn&amp;rsquo;t meant as an introduction to any of the topics discussed below. Instead, it&amp;rsquo;s a brief guide on how to make the Markdown-Preview plugin work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Neo)vim is, for the most part, the only editor I use for all my needs -— whether it&amp;rsquo;s programming, editing configuration files, or taking notes. I write all of my notes in Markdown for several reasons: it&amp;rsquo;s widely compatible, has easy-to-understand syntax, is very readable even without rendering, and, through various flavors, allows for additional functionality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Card Game from my Childhood</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/card_game_childhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/card_game_childhood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;preliminary&#34;&gt;Preliminary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was in elementary school, I attended a school that ran all day. After each lesson, we had short breaks, along with three longer breaks: one in the morning, one at lunchtime, and another in the afternoon. The morning breaks are the most memorable for me. During these breaks, the entire school was sent out to the schoolyard, and no one was allowed inside, unlike the other breaks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a person? Or when is a person?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/when_does_a_something_deserve_moral_considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/when_does_a_something_deserve_moral_considerations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;&#xA;    .info {&#xA;        background-color: #e6f7ff;  &#xA;        padding: 15px;  &#xA;        border-radius: 5px;  &#xA;        margin-bottom: 15px;  &#xA;    }&#xA;&#xA;    .info-title {&#xA;        font-size: 20px;  &#xA;        margin-bottom: 10px;  &#xA;        color: #000080;  &#xA;        font-weight: bold;  &#xA;    }&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;info&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;info-title&#34;&gt;Info&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;This post is incomplete, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t hold every argument or consideration for every position, just some.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It would not be a controversial statement to say, that a person deserves moral consideration i.e. when doing an action involving another person one must consider the morality of the action. For example most people would agree that murdering a person is wrong, because in general we think that each person has a right to live, which gets infringed through the action of murder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neovim Tricks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/neovim_cheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/neovim_cheatsheet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a short cheat sheet for important keybindings in vim more specific for neovim. I am using &lt;a href=&#34;https://nvchad.com/&#34;&gt;NVChad&lt;/a&gt; as such not all keybindings are applicable to standard vim/nvim.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Capitalization is important!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ESC&lt;/code&gt;, switch to normal mode.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;v&lt;/code&gt;, switch to visual mode.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt;, switch to insert mode.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt;, replace mode.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Navigation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;arrow keys&lt;/code&gt;, shame on you!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Movement keys, can be combined with arbitrary number&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;h&lt;/code&gt;, to the left.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;l&lt;/code&gt;, to the right.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;j&lt;/code&gt;, downwards.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;k&lt;/code&gt;, upwards.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Example: &lt;code&gt;10j&lt;/code&gt; jumps 10 lines downwards, &lt;code&gt;5k&lt;/code&gt; jumps 4 lines upwards.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;_&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt;, beginning of the line.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt;, to the end of the line.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;e&lt;/code&gt;, one word forward.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt;, one word backward.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:NUMBER&lt;/code&gt;, jumps to the line number.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;f&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;CHAR&lt;/code&gt;, jumps to the &lt;em&gt;next&lt;/em&gt; character matching the input char.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;CHAR&lt;/code&gt;, jumps to the &lt;em&gt;previous&lt;/em&gt; character matching the input char.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gg&lt;/code&gt;, moves to the &lt;em&gt;top&lt;/em&gt; of the files.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;G&lt;/code&gt;, moves to the &lt;em&gt;bottom&lt;/em&gt; of the file.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;20G&lt;/code&gt;, moves cursor to line 20.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Navigating Code:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab Part 12: Outlook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_12_outlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 08:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_12_outlook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The software I have showcased in this Homelab series is just a fraction of the applications that you can host yourself on your server.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, I would like to share some additional intriguing software that I plan to explore in the future, or that are generally cool projects:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jellyfin.org/&#34;&gt;Jellyfin&lt;/a&gt;: A media software system that allows you to manage movies, TV shows, and music, and stream them to various devices.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Radarr/Sonarr/Readarr/Lidarr/Bazaar: These are movie, TV show, book, music, and subtitle torrent finder that enable you to search for torrents of your favorite media. When combined with BitTorrent, they can download the media and place it in your Jellyfin media library.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Fallenbagel/jellyseerr&#34;&gt;Jellyseer&lt;/a&gt;:  This tool can be used with Jellyfin and the &amp;ldquo;arr&amp;rdquo; services to request and download media&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/paperless-ngx/paperless-ngx&#34;&gt;Paperless-Ngx&lt;/a&gt;: A document management software that transforms all your physical documents into a searchable online archive, eliminating the need for physical paperwork.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://immich.app/&#34;&gt;Immich&lt;/a&gt;A self-hosted photo and video manager and backup solution for your photos, offering an impressive set of features rivaling apps like Google Photos.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pi-hole.net/&#34;&gt;Pi-Hole&lt;/a&gt;: A network wide ad-blocker. It eliminates the need to install an ad-blocker on each device, allowing you to block ads for all your devices with just one software. It can also serve as your own DNS server.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/topics/offline/quick_start_guide.html&#34;&gt;GitLab&lt;/a&gt;: : Similar to GitHub, GitLab allows you to host your own Git projects online and share them with others.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/EmulatorJS/EmulatorJS&#34;&gt;EmulatorJS&lt;/a&gt;: Enables playing retro games over a web browser from anywhere, as long as you have an internet connection.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://invidious.io/&#34;&gt;Invidious&lt;/a&gt;: An open-source alternative frontend for YouTube that allows you to download videos and manage them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mealie-recipes/mealie&#34;&gt;mealie&lt;/a&gt;: A self-hosted recipe manager and meal planner.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/advplyr/audiobookshelf&#34;&gt;audiobookshelf&lt;/a&gt;: A self-hosted audiobook and podcast server.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hope you discover one or two interesting software applications from this list!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab Part 11: Backup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_11_backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 11:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_11_backup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It goes without saying that backups are crucial. If you aim to preserve your data for the future, proper backup practices are a necessity. The golden rule of backing up is the 3-2-1 rule, which advises having three copies of your data, on two different media, with one copy off-site.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my case, I needed a backup solution for various types of data:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photos&lt;/strong&gt;: Currently stored on my phone.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Text files&lt;/strong&gt;: Including university notes, general notes, and articles, currently saved on my computers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Configuration files&lt;/strong&gt;: From my server, currently saved on the SD card of the server.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For my backup needs, I opted for two solutions: &lt;strong&gt;Syncthing&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;rsync&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab Part 10: Vaultwarden</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_10_vaultwarden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 11:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_10_vaultwarden/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vaultwarden is an unofficial implementation of the Bitwarden password manager. One of its primary advantages is its lower resource intensity for hosting compared to the official implementation, along with the support of a robust community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img style=&#34;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width:100%&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/8ddd4488bb9c1a355dc41d6b6db4898f.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;Vaultwarden Website.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before adopting Vaultwarden, I relied on the offline password manager KeePassXC. However, it posed challenges with synchronization across multiple devices. For instance, if I altered a password on my phone, I had to transfer the entire password database to my computer to ensure synchronization. In contrast, Vaultwarden streamlines this process by automatically synchronizing password changes across all devices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab Part 9: Caddy, FileServer and DuckDNS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_9_caddy_fileserver_and_duckdns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 11:32:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_9_caddy_fileserver_and_duckdns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have been following this Homelab series, you probably have several services up and running, and maybe even a homepage linking to all your services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Up to this point, however, accessing these services outside your home network was not possible, and the services lacked user-friendly, readable domain names. Instead, you had to enter the IP address of your server followed by the port of the service you wanted to access. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be nice if you could access your services like this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab Part 8: Homepage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_8_homepage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 18:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_8_homepage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have been following my Homelab Series so far, you probably have quite a number of services running, and perhaps you&amp;rsquo;re losing track of all your services. In that case, you might want to consider having a central page that links to all your hosted services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gethomepage/homepage&#34;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt; is a highly customizable, fully static, fast, and modern dashboard with integration for many services. It allows users to see all running services at a glance and can be easily configured by editing a YAML file.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab Part 7: UptimeKuma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_7_uptimekuma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 18:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_7_uptimekuma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe at some point you have encountered a situation where, while running all your current containers, you tried accessing one of your services only to realize that the service is not available because the container exited without your knowledge?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For such Issues, it&amp;rsquo;s beneficial to have a notification system that can automatically alert you whenever a container exits or is no longer available.  To address this need, I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://uptime.kuma.pet/&#34;&gt;UptimeKuma&lt;/a&gt;, an easy-to-use self-hosted monitoring tool. UptimeKuma can monitor uptime over means like HTTP(s)/TCP/Ping/Docker/DNS and notify you via various channels such as Telegram, Discord, Gotify, Slack, Email, and more. Additionally, it provides a user-friendly web interface for managing and adding new monitors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab Part 6: Syncthing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_6_syncthing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 16:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_6_syncthing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this installment, I explore another valuable use case for my server - file synchronization between my various devices. This includes regular backups of the pictures taken on my phone, archiving important documents, and seamless access to notes across all devices for tasks like blogging, to-dos, projects, and university-related work. To accomplish this, I rely on the powerful capabilities of &lt;a href=&#34;https://syncthing.net/&#34;&gt;synthing&lt;/a&gt; a continuous file synchronization program.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Syncthing operates by synchronizing files between two or more devices, akin to the functionality of OneDrive synchronization on Windows. However, instead of storing files on a cloud server, Syncthing saves them locally on my home server. The software comes equipped with a user-friendly WebUI that facilitates easy management of file synchronization and connected devices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab Part 5: HomeAssistant with Zigbee2MQTT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_5_homeassistant_with_zigbee2mqtt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 11:34:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_5_homeassistant_with_zigbee2mqtt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I hinted in my initial post of this series, &amp;ldquo;My Homelab Part 0: Prologue,&amp;rdquo; my motivation for incorporating Home Assistant into my server revolves around dynamically scheduling the lights in my room. This functionality enables me to wake up gradually with softly illuminated surroundings and help me fall asleep with lights that gradually fade away. However, Home Assistant&amp;rsquo;s capabilities extend beyond light control.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Home Assistant is a free and open-source software designed for home automation. Functioning as the central control system for smart homes, it can be accessed either through an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/home-assistant/android/releases&#34;&gt;android app&lt;/a&gt; or a web-based interface.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab Part 4: Wireguard VPN</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_4_wireguard_vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 11:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_4_wireguard_vpn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I need access to my home server to work on some configuration files or check the health of the server, but not always do I have physical access to my home server. One way to still get access to my server even when I am far away is through a VPN, which allows me to connect to my home network, and from the home network, I can then SSH into my home server.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab Part 3: Calibre</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_3_calibre/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 11:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_3_calibre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my free time, I enjoy reading books. For a long time, I organized the books I read on physical paper notes. However, as the list grew longer and paper deteriorated over time, I realized it was impractical. To address this, I decided to switch to a digital organization strategy, and for that, I chose the software Calibre.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Calibre is a free and open-source e-book management program. It supports organizing existing e-books into virtual libraries, displaying and editing e-books, and even synchronizing them with different e-readers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab Part 2: DietPi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_2_dietpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 11:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_2_dietpi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like mentioned in my last blog post in the &amp;ldquo;Homelab&amp;rdquo; series, I choose DietPi as operating system for my server.&#xA;In this post I want to give a short overview on the installation process and other miscellaneous aspects related to it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Installation Guide&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The installation process for DietPi may vary slightly from one computer to another, but the steps outlined below should be applicable to most setups. This guide is specifically tailored for Raspberry Pi, but it can be adapted for other systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab Part 1: Introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_1_introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 15:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_1_introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my previous blog post in the Homelab Series, I shared how the need to maintain a regular sleep schedule led me to the idea of running my own server at home, which I affectionately call my &amp;ldquo;homelab.&amp;rdquo; The primary purpose of this homelab is to control the smart lights in my room through Home Assistant.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, I want to provide an overview about the different technologies I employed for running my Homelab.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Poetry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/introduction_to_poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 23:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/introduction_to_poetry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Poetry has long been an mystery to me - Never understood why people like it, never understood the need for analyzing them in school and especially never understood why people treat it so highly.&#xA;It always felt similar to the esoteric behavior displayed by wine snobs about what the perfect wine is.&#xA;However, as my interest recently shifted to world building. I began to recognize the potential within poetry as story telling tool, realizing it could serve as integral role to craft religions and history of the world.&#xA;Moreover, when looking into the history of writing and books than its clear that poetry predates modern novels and as such it&amp;rsquo;s interesting on it own how this came to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is PGP/GPG?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what_is_pgp_gpg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 17:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what_is_pgp_gpg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;&#xA;    .info {&#xA;        background-color: #e6f7ff;  &#xA;        padding: 15px;  &#xA;        border-radius: 5px;  &#xA;        margin-bottom: 15px;  &#xA;    }&#xA;&#xA;    .info-title {&#xA;        font-size: 20px;  &#xA;        margin-bottom: 10px;  &#xA;        color: #000080;  &#xA;        font-weight: bold;  &#xA;    }&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;info&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;info-title&#34;&gt;Info&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;In this post, I provide an example of implementing digital signatures for blog posts. While this method works, I no longer use it due to a switch in my Hugo theme for my website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To quote Wikipedia, &amp;ldquo;Pretty Good Privacy (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pretty_Good_Privacy&#34;&gt;PGP&lt;/a&gt;) is an encryption program that provides cryptographic privacy and authentication for data communication.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;It is widely used for sending encrypted emails, encrypting sensitive files and digitally signing files.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Convolutional Neural Network</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/proseminar_cnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/proseminar_cnn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;&#xA;    .info {&#xA;        background-color: #e6f7ff;  &#xA;        padding: 15px;  &#xA;        border-radius: 5px;  &#xA;        margin-bottom: 15px;  &#xA;    }&#xA;&#xA;    .info-title {&#xA;        font-size: 20px;  &#xA;        margin-bottom: 10px;  &#xA;        color: #000080;  &#xA;        font-weight: bold;  &#xA;    }&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;info&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;info-title&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;I wrote this article back in uni as part of the seminar, &amp;quot;Basics of Machine Learning 1 &amp;amp; 2&amp;quot;. As such this text only introduces some basic concepts and is limited in scope.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, significant advancements have been made in the field of Machine Learning, particularly in the domain of image-related tasks. This paper aims to provide a comprehensive overview of Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs), a powerful class of neural networks widely employed for image analysis and processing. In addition to that, this paper presents a self-trained CNN model specifically designed for digit classification. The model achieves solid performance in accurately classifying hand-drawn digits. By shedding light on the inner workings of CNNs and showcasing their practical application in digit classification, I seek to encourage further research and development in this domain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How did I created my website?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how_did_i_created_my_website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 20:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how_did_i_created_my_website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;&#xA;    .warning {&#xA;        background-color: #ffe4e1;  &#xA;        padding: 15px;  &#xA;        border-radius: 5px;  &#xA;        margin-bottom: 15px;  &#xA;    }&#xA;&#xA;    .warning-title {&#xA;        font-size: 20px;  &#xA;        margin-bottom: 10px;  &#xA;        color: #8b0000;  &#xA;        font-weight: bold;  &#xA;    }&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;warning-title&#34;&gt;Info&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&#xA;This post is outdated, I do not use the theme specified in this post anymore.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post primarily serves as documentation for my website. Additionally, if someone finds something useful here, they are welcome to use it. The entire source code, including blog posts and their digital signatures, can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MonkeManX/monkemanx.github.io&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab Part 0: Prologue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_0_prologue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 10:13:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_homelab_part_0_prologue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately, maintaining a consistent sleeping schedule has posed big challenge for me.&#xA;Different university courses have lead me to wake up on some days as early as 6 a.m., while on other days, I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself rising as late as 12. p.m .&#xA;This irregular sleeping schedule has been quite a struggle, especially on days where I had to get up early.&#xA;My body, accustomed to my late-night schedule, could never fall asleep soon enough for a well-rested morning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
